Now that we have our skis put on appropriately, and we have our correct size poles match up, the next thing to do is learning how to actually Nordic ski.
Learning the correct technique.
The really wonderful thing about Nordic skiing is it's a great sport that people enjoy doing, and look forward to it every winter in the snow.
It's also great exercise because you're getting a full body workout.
You're using your arms, your legs, and your core as well.
A lot of people wonder what's the appropriate way to move my feet and arms when I Nordic ski.
Patrick is going to demonstrate that.
You want to swing both your opposite foot and arm in front of you, and push off.
And the way I like to describe it is, remember when you were a little kid and you'd run through your mom's kitchen with your socks on and slide around.
That's all your doing.
And each time you do that you sort of push off and kick up your heel and push off that way.
And just sort of like your doing a forward moon walk in your socks in the kitchen.